<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Bay Area on Circle: Build your own system</title>
    <link>https://usistem.com/en/the-bay-area/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Bay Area on Circle: Build your own system</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://usistem.com/en/the-bay-area/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Get started with self tracking？</title>
      <link>https://usistem.com/en/the-bay-area/get-started-with-self-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 14:33:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usistem.com/en/the-bay-area/get-started-with-self-tracking/</guid>
      <description>This article is from：https://quantifiedself.com/get-started/ , you can read original article by clicking the link. There&amp;rsquo;s no change of content, just there&amp;rsquo;s no way to redirect to source directly.
The purpose of this website is to support anybody who wants to use empirical methods to explore personal questions. We call this practice “everyday science.” In the decade that we’ve been working with people doing self-tracking projects, we’ve come to appreciate the diversity of motivations, methods and tools people use to gain insight into a problem or question using their own data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The bay Area Weekly No.1</title>
      <link>https://usistem.com/en/the-bay-area/the-bay-area-weekly-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 11:22:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usistem.com/en/the-bay-area/the-bay-area-weekly-01/</guid>
      <description>This is the first issue of &amp;ldquo;Bay Area Weekly&amp;rdquo; maintained by @HagerHu . Bay Area Weekly focuses on the internet, technology, and entrepreneurship in the Bay Area. Make progress every week.
750 Words 750 Words是《艺术家的方式》中所学到的晨间页面的数字版本，由 @buster 创立，用于日常记录私人日志，750 差不多是 3 页纸的字数。写作，可以在记录的过程中了解自己。
750 Words is basically a digital version of morning pages, an idea I learned about from Julia Cameron&amp;rsquo;s The Artist&amp;rsquo;s Way. It is founded by @buster for daily personal journaling. 750 is the words count of three standard pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paul Graham：How to start a startup?</title>
      <link>https://usistem.com/en/the-bay-area/how-to-start-a-startup-paul-graham/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 11:22:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usistem.com/en/the-bay-area/how-to-start-a-startup-paul-graham/</guid>
      <description>This article is from http://paulgraham.com/start.html 。Original article writen by years ago, not friendly for reading since less line content. This article is just formated for reading experience, no changes of content.
You need three things to create a successful startup: to start with good people, to make something customers actually want, and to spend as little money as possible. Most startups that fail do it because they fail at one of these.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
